Staudinger, Hans; Papers ger087
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Hans Staudinger Papers
1928-1980
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger087
31.5 cubic ft.
Staudinger was a Social Democratic Party member of the Reichstag until his removal by the Nazis in 1933; he was professor of economics at the University in Exile from 1934 and dean of the graduate faculty of the New School for Social Research at various times between 1941 and 1960. The collection contains articles, books, diplomas, passports, photographs, scrapbooks, Festscrifen, and memorabilia of Hans Staudinger and members of his family. It also contains correspondence; handwritten and typed drafts of lecture notes, speeches, and addresses; teaching and research materials; and publications by Hans Staudinger and members of the New School for Social Research. The concentration of material is in the period of 1940 through 1960, with early biographical material dating from 1907 and some items dating through 1980.
Biographical Sketch
Biographical information was gathered from the private papers of Dr. Staudinger.
Chronology
1889 August 16 - born at Worms am Rhein, Germany, son of Franz and Auguste (Wenck) Staudinger
1907 Graduated from Altes Gymnasium, Darmstadt
1907/8 Studied literature during the winter semester at the University of Munich
1908 Studied during the spring semester at the University of Heidelberg
1908/1913 Studied economics and sociology from the fall semester of 1908 until the summer semester of 1913 at the University of Heidelberg
1913 Received his doctorate in economics and sociology from the University of Heidelberg, summa cum laude. Doctoral dissertation was Individuum und Gemeinscbaft
1913 December a contract with the publisher Eugen Diedrichs, Jena, to publish his book, Individuum und Gemeinschaft
1913/14 Served as Revisionssekretaer, Sueddeutscher Verband der Konsum ereine
1914 Military service in the German army
1916 May 18 - decorated with the Eiserne Kreuz II. Klasse 10. Kompanie des Infantrie Regiment Markgraf Ludwig Wilhelm (3. Bad) Nr. III
1918 Appointed as Referent in the Kriegsernaehrulngsamt, Berlin. Appointed Regierungsrat, Berlin
1921 Appointed Geheimer Regieru-ngsrat, Reichswirtschafts-Ministerium, Berlin
1922 Appointed Geheimer Regierungsrat and Ministerialrat, Berlin
1919/24 Served as personal adjudant to the Reichswirtschafts-Ministers Robert Schmidt, Scholz, Neuhaus, von Raumer, Koeth and Hamm; served as Referent for the Reichswirtschaftsrat and.the Deutsche Enquete Commission
1927 Became Ministerialdirektor in the Preussischen Handelsministerium for Elektrizitaetswirtschaft, Hafen- und Verkehrsangelegenheiten
1927/33 Served as a member of the Reichstag
1929 Served as Staatssekretaer in the Preussischen Handelsministerium, as Aufsichtsrat-Vorsitzender of the Harbors Duisburg and Stettin, of the Preussen Elektra, of the Preusaag, and of the Vereinigten Elektrizitaets - und Bergwerkgesellschaft
1931 His book Der Staat als Unternehmer, published by Gersbach und Sohn, Berlin
1932/33 Elected a member of the Reichstag, Sozialdemokratische Partei, Hamburg
1932 Removed by Chancellor Franz von Papen from his positions in government after the fall of the constitutional government
1933 SJune 16 to July 22: held in police custody in Hamburg and prosecuted by the Nazis
1933 August 30 officially discharged from his positions in government
1933 Emigrated to Belgium
1933 Consultant to SOFINA, Brussels SOFINA association from 1933 1939
1934 Studied during the spring semester at the University of Heidelberg
1934 Fall - appointed Professor for Economics at the University in Exile, New School for Social Research, New York
1940 September 26 - became a naturalized citizen: No. 4 776 622 (certificate of naturalization), Southern District of New York, District Court of the U. S. A.
1941/43 Served as Dean of the Graduate Faculty at the New School for Social Research, New York
1943/53 Chairman of the Council for Research, Institute Of World Affairs (Director from 1951-1953)
1944 September 29 - received notification of termination of appointment as "Expert" from the U. S. War Department
1950/51 Served as Dean of the Graduate Faculty at the New School for Social Research, New York
1951/53 Chairman of the Institute of World Affairs
1955/60 Served as Dean of the Graduate Faculty at the New School for Social Research, New York
1959 April 6 - received the Honorary Degree of Doctor of Laws from the New School of Social Research, New York
1959/64 Editor of the Journal of Social Research, an International Quarterly of Political Social Science, New York, (published by the New School for Social Research)
1960 Elected Professor Emeritus, New School for Social Research, New York
1963 Laying of the ground stone at the Dampfkraftwerk Staudinger, Grosskrotzen- burg, Hanau/Main, Germany
1965 Endowment of a permanent Faculty Chair, Else and Hans Staudinger, New School for Social Research, New York
1965 September 16- Opening ceremonies Dampfkraftwerk Staudinger, Gross krotzenburg, Hanau/Main, Germany
1966 March 1966-death of his wife, Else Staudinger
1966 October 29 married Elizabeth Todd (born April.3, 1903) in St. Joseph, Missouri)
1969 August 24 received the Cross of Merit with Star from the Federal Republic of West-Germany (was informed of this by the German Counsul Dr. Klaus Curtius)
1969 October 15 became a duly elected member of the German Society of the City of New York
1980 February 25 died in Manhattan
Scope and Contents
The papers of Hans Staudinger reflect his professional, political, and cultural activities in Germany and the United States. His teaching materials concentrate on economics and sociology and are world-wide in scope. Materials are in English or German, with the correspondence and lecture notes pertaining to the New School for Social Research being predominantly in English.
The collection contains articles, books, diplomas, passports, photographs, scrapbooks, Festscrifen, and memorabilia of Hans Staudinger and members of his family. It also contains correspondence; handwritten and typed drafts of lecture notes, speeches, and addresses; teaching and research materials; and publications by Hans Staudinger and members of the New School for Social Research. The concentration of material is in the period of 1940 through 1960, with early biographical material dating from 1907 and some items dating through 1980.
Included in the collection are records of the activities of Dr. Else Staudinger (first wife of Dr. Hans Staudinger) on behalf of the American Council for Emigrés in the Professions, Inc.
The correspondence and other items relating to the Staudinger family are of interest because of the importance of the individuals involved. Dr. Staudinger's father, Dr. Franz Staudinger, was a philosopher and sociologist, a consumer activist, served as a Lutheran pastor and university professor, and wrote on ethics, philosophy, and religion. His sister, Louise Federn-Staudinger, was a renowned sculpturist. His brother, Dr. Hermann Staudinger, considered to be the founder of molecular chemistry, was a university professor who won the Nobel Prize for chemistry in 1953, was noted for his inspirational teaching, and was the author of over 500 books and papers in the field of organic chemistry. His, nephew, Dr. Hansjürgen Staudinger, was a professor of physiological chemistry and Director of the Biochemical Department at the University of Giessen.
Other correspondence (with over 200 individuals and organizations) covers Staudinger's many interests and activities: university education, aid to exiles, Deutsche Theater, public utilities, assistance to colleagues and students in publishing their writings, arrangements for publishing his own works. Of special interest might be the correspondence and records pertaining to foreign scholars and other professionals rescued from the Nazis; the activities of the American Council for Emigrés in the Professions, Inc., and the Rockefeller Foundation in their behalf; and the correspondence on the efforts to resettle these individuals in the United States. There are materials which relate to the professional activities of Dr. Hans Staudinger as a member of the various ministries in Berlin between the years of 1918 to 1932, and also which deal with his extensive efforts to bring about an expanded cultural exchange between Germany and the United States after the end of the Second World War.
Holdings relative to the New School deal with its inception under Alvin Johnson, historical items from the observances of the School's 25th and 40th anniversaries, the work of the Rockefeller Foundation in aiding exiles, and copies of publications by 26 members.
Typescripts of Staudinger's articles, speeches, books, and book reviews are held in the manuscript section of the Collection, together with many of his publications. (Published works can be found in the book section by using the card catalog.).
The bulk of the collection consists of lecture and research materials, Topics with large amounts of materials are: Ecology, Economics, Education, Electricity, Energy, Foreign Affairs, Foreign Trade, German Business and Government, Common Market, Industry and Labor, Inflation, Leisure Time, Money, Peace, Philosophy, Politics, Population Growth, Psychology, Religion, Socialism, Sociology. These research materials include pamphlets, clippings, and some correspondence with individuals who were experts in the specific field.
The Hans Staudinger Papers are of interest to researchers in the fields of economics, sociology, educational history and theory (especially on the university level), history of German-speaking exiles. Researchers in the fields of science might want to examine the correspondence and publications of Dr. Hermann Staudinger, his wife, Dr. Magda Staudinger, and his son, Dr. Hans Jürgen Staudinger.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: Biographical materials
Series 2: Correspondence
Series 3: New School
Series 4: Organizations and Associations
Series 5: Writings, speeches, etc.
Series 6: Lectures and notes
Series 7: Subjects: Individuals
Series 8: Teaching and research materials
Series 9: Writings
Series 10: Miscellaneous
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Elizabeth Todd Staudinger (Mrs. Hans Staudinger) in 1980.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Economics; World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees.; Economics -- Study and teaching.; World politics.; Staudinger, Hans, 1889-1980.; Johnson, Alvin.; Kracauer, Siegfried, 1889-1966.; Lederer, Emil, 1882-1939.; Lowe, Adolph, 1893-; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Stolper, Toni.; Staudinger, Franz, 1849-1921.; Staudinger, Else.; Arnold, Fritz.; Brecht, Arnold, 1884-1977.; Curtius, Klaus.; Grossman, Kurt.; Heilbroner, Robert L.; Heinemann, Gustav Walter, 1899-1976.; Heuss, Theodor, 1884-1963.; American Council for Emigres in the Professions.
- Biographical materials, 1933-1969; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical sketches; documents regarding education, employment, imprisonment (1933), and activities of Hans Staudinger and members of his family; family history; photographs.
  - Staudinger, Hans - Biographical documents, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 1)
  - Staudinger, Hans - Biographical sketches, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 2)
  - Staudinger, Hans - Darmstadt (views, history, etc), Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 3)
  - Staudinger, Hans - Travel diary, ca. 1930 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 4)
  - Staudinger, Hans - Imprisonment and loss of position: Germany, 1933 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 5)
  - Staudinger, Hans - New School (Appointments, awards, etc), Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 6)
  - Staudinger, Hans - Consultant in the U.S. War Department, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 7)
  - Staudinger, Hans - 80th birthday, 1969 August 16 (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 8)
  - Staudinger, Hans - Miscellaneous notes, names, addresses, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 9)
  - Staudinger, Hans - Newspaper clippings, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 10)
  - Staudinger, Hans - Offers of positions, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 11)
  - Staudinger, Hans - Photographs (also photographs of family members), Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 12)
  - Staudinger, Hans - "Poesie Album" (also dried clover leafs), Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 13)
  - Staudinger, Hans - Residences, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 14)
  - Staudinger family - Correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 15)
  - Staudinger family - General, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 16)
  - Staudinger family - History, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 17)
  - Staudinger, Else - Documents, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 18)
  - Staudinger, Else - American Council for Emigrés in the Professions, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 19)
  - Staudinger, Else - ACEP, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 20)
  - Staudinger, Else - Biographical sketches, photographs, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 21)
  - Staudinger, Else - Death, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 22)
  - Staudinger, Else - Memorial, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 23)
  - Staudinger, Frank (son), Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 24)
  - Staudinger, Franz, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 25-26)
  - Staudinger, Franz - Publications, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 27)
  - Staudinger, Hansjürgen, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 28-29)
  - Staudinger, Hermann, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 30-32)
  - Staudinger, Magda, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 33)
  - Staudinger, Wilhelm, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 34)
  - Staudinger, Jan Jacek, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 35)
  - Federn-Staudinger, Louise, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 36)
  - Schaffner, Ruth (Mrs. Joseph Halle Schaffner), Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 37)
  - Dampfkraftwerk Staudinger, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical materials), Folder 38)
- Correspondence, 1933-1980; 2
  Personal and professional correspondence.
  Note: Correspondence is scattered throughout the Collection.
  - Unsorted, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1-2)
  - Unsorted, 1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Unsorted, 1964 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Unsorted, 1965-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Unsorted, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - New Year's letter, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
    with reply by Adolph Lowe.
  - Easter letter, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
    with replies.
  - New Year's letter, 1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Easter letter, 1975 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Unsorted, 1973-1977 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Unsorted, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12-13)
  - Arnold, Fritz, re: Otto Stegemann, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Balint, Maria, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Barclay, David, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Behrens, Henry W., Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Bennigsen-Foerder, R. von, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Berks, David, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Boehm, Eric, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Brandt, Willy, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Braun, Otto, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Brecht, Arnold, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - re: Broch, Hermann, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Curtius, Klaus, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Deutsche Theater, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Dewall, Hans von, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Eynern, Gert von, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Ferraro, Eugene, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Fetscher, Iring, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Fischer-Dieskau, Joachim, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Fisher, Louis, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Flitner, Hugbert, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Gambke, Gotthard, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Gehlhoff, Walter, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - Germer, Edmund, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Gideonse, Harry, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - Gontard, Gert von, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - Grathoff, Richard re: Carl Mayer, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Grossman, Kurt, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Grubbe, Peter, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - Hamburger, Ernest re: Henry Salfeld, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - Hartmann, Alfred, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - Heilbronner, Robert, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - Heilbrunn, Alfred, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
  - Heilbut, Anthony, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Heineman, D. N., Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
  - Heinemann, Gustav, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
  - Heinemann, James H., Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 49)
  - Henle, Mary, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
  - Heuss, Theodor, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
  - Hirsch, Felix E., Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
  - Hoffmann, Julius, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53)
  - Iggers, Georg, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 54)
  - Initiative Committee for National Economic Planning, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 55)
  - Jacoby, E. G., Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 56-57)
  - Jaeggi, Urs, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Joachimowski, Alfons, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Johnson, Alvin, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines re: Vietnam War, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Jonas, Hans, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Junior, Peter, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Katona, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Kiep, Walther Leisler, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Kohl, Heinrich, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Kollege re: SPD Parteiprogramme (vor 1933), Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Kollegen von Reichswirtschafts ministerium, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Kracauer, E., Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Krimmel, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Lachman, Charles S., Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Landauer, Carl, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Landmann, Michael, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Lash, Trude, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - re: Lederer, Emil, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Lennard, Henry L., Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Leser, Paul, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Lowenthal, Richard, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Lohaus, Adam H., Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Lorch, Jack and Louise, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Lowe, Adolf, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Lowe, Adolf re: Government policy on Vietnam, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Lowe, Adolf re: Hans Jonas, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Lowe, Adolph, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Luckmann, Benita, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Ludz, Peter Christian, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Luhmann, Niklas, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Malaquais, Elisabeth, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - re: Mannheim, Karl, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Marx, Henry, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - re: Mayr, Karl (Hitler's instruction officer), Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Mocsanyi, Paul, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - Möller, Alex, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Naterp, Paul, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - Paetel, Karl Otto, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - Popitz, Heinrich, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Raabe, P., Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Ragg, Albrecht, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - Riemer, Jehuda, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - re: Riezler, Kurt, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - Roemer, Wilhelm, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - Romoser, George K., Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 45)
  - Rosenfeld, Theodore, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Rüstow, Hanns-Joachim, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 47)
  - Rutkoff, Peter, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 48)
  - Sahl, Hans, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 49)
  - Salz, Beate, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 50)
    (including two photographs).
  - Schaeffer, Eva, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 51)
  - Schaeffer, Hans, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 52)
  - re: Schaeffer, Hans-Festscrift, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 53-58)
  - Schaffner, Ruth S., Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 59)
  - Schalfejew, Eduard, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 60)
  - Schilling, Hermann, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 61)
  - Schmidt-Schlegel, Philipp, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 62)
  - Siches, Recasens, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 63)
  - Simmel, Marianne L., Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 64)
  - Simons, Hans, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 65)
  - Spalek, John, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 66)
  - Spangenberg, Gisela, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 67)
  - Speier, Hans, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 68-69)
  - Speier, Hans re: Emil Lederer, Max Weber, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 70)
  - Spier, Fred, Undated (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 71)
  - Spitz, Rose (Quotations from Gibran, etc), Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Staden, Berndt von, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Stahl, Walter, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Stegemann, Otto, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Steltzer, Theodor, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Stetzer, Werner, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Stern, Frederick M., Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Stolper, Toni, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Strauss, Herbert, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Strauss, Leo re: Howard White, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Strauss, Walter, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Tauber, Esther, Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Tenbruck, Friedrick H., Undated (Box 4 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)